(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Darkness will fade away,
Light will guide your way,
Hope has descended and
...you are not alone.
Caesura of Despair
Lyrics / Composition: buzzG
道と雨が織りなす
A contrast woven by
コントラスト
the road and the rain
絶望の終わりを願うように
As if wishing for the end of despair
ここにいるよ
I am here,
歌ってるよ
I am singing
夜明けの果てを
Looking towards the edge of dawn
こぼれ落ちた
The spilled
黄昏のエレジー
twilight elegy
凍えた心
Saying farewell
涙にサヨナラ
to the frozen heart's tears
きっと Despair
I'll sing so that despair
晴れるように　歌うから
will surely clear up
そして Make a wish
And then I'll make a wish
鮮やかに　飾るから
and decorate it vividly
Darkness will fade away,
Hope will lead your way,
I'm here to chant the
melodies for you.
月と星が彩るサテライト
A satellite colored by the moon and stars
暗闇も君となら飛べるよ
If I'm with you, I can fly even through darkness
夜だからこそ
Because it is night,
輝ける
there must be light
光もあるでしょう
that can shine through
忘れないで　君のためのセレナーデ
Don't forget, a serenade just for you
壊れかけた　夢の続きをここで見よう
Let's see the rest of the broken dream here
Resize your story,
Time is running too fast and left behind.
It's all mine.
運命に駆け寄っていこう
Let's run toward destiny
黒い指に沈む君の手に
Into your hand sinking into black fingers
届け
Reach out
願ってるよ 未来の足音
I'm wishing, the footsteps of the future
手と手をつなごう オーケストラ
Let's join hands, orchestra
懐かしくも淡い歌で
With a nostalgic and faint song
奏でて
Playing
夜明けが聞こえる
The dawn can be heard
Believe in destiny 約束を果たすから
Believe in destiny, because I'll fulfill my promise
いつか理由に 語りきれないほど響いて
One day, let it resonate so much that it can't be told as a reason
嘆きも後悔も 笑い飛ばそうよ
Let's laugh off the grief and regrets
そんな形に 希望と名付けよう
Let's name such forms "hope"
きっと
Surely
Despair 晴れるように歌うから
I'll sing so that despair clears up
そして Make a wish 鮮やかに飾るから
And make a wish, because I'll decorate it vividly
君だけの声と 重ねるように
So that it overlaps with only your voice
こんな世界だって 側にいるよ
Even in a world like this, I'll be by your side
Darkness fade away
Iris will light your way
Our journey has only just begun right now
HiRyS! It's IRyS!
in 3D from Hololive English! Woo!
Thank you so much guys for coming to my 3D showcase!
3Dお披露目に来てくださってありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to my 3D showcase!
I fell from a very, very high height, but I got wings so I'm fine.
落ちたけど全然大丈夫だよ！
I fell but I'm totally fine!
この素敵なステージ見てください。
Please check out this wonderful stage.
Thank you! Please check out my beautiful stage in the middle of a big city,
and that beautiful red tower behind, yes!
めっちゃ美しい赤いタワーと、すごい、めちゃくちゃ都会です。
With that beautiful red tower, it's very urban.
IRyS、都会っ子です。
IRyS is a city girl.
I am a city girl. Very much a city girl.
I'm going to be singing a lot of songs on this stage. I'm so excited!
Alrighty, so this is just the start,
but if you have any thoughts about my 3D showcase,
or if you want to tweet about it, please use the hashtag #3DRyS right here.
Yes, please use the hashtag to tweet. Let's go!
There's going to be a lot of fun stuff.
Alrighty then. I can move so much now!
Look at me! Look at this beautiful IRyS movement!
Like I said in my hype, beautiful IRyS movement!
Anyways, I'm going to be singing a lot more.
So, let's get to it then, yeah? Let's get to the next song.
Alrighty, 次の曲聴いてください。
Alrighty, please listen to the next song.
Shangri-La.
ほら、風が吹いているのだろう
Look, the wind must be blowing
見渡す夢の跡
Looking over the remains of a dream
サヨナラ 蒼き日々よ
Goodbye, blue days
Shangri-La
流れに身を任せ いつか大人になってゆき
Leaving myself to the flow, becoming an adult one day
少しずつ汚れてゆく事なの？
Is it about becoming a little dirty bit by bit?
熟した果実が...
A ripened fruit...
...だけ 選ばれて
...only, I was chosen
鳴り響いた
It resounded
叫ばれて
It was shouted
飲み込まれる前に
Before being swallowed up
僕らは目指した シャングリラ
We aimed for Shangri-La
欲望を抑えきれずに
Unable to restrain our desires
空想にまみれた
Covered in fantasies
自由を求め続けた
We continued to seek freedom
今なら言えるだろう
I can probably say it now
ここがユートピア
This place is Utopia
さよなら 蒼き日々よ
Goodbye, blue days
哀切な顔
A sorrowful face
踏み台にしてまでも
Even if I make it a stepping stone
一番高いリンゴ
The highest apple
掴みたかった
I wanted to grasp it
失くしてから気付く
Realizing after losing it
尊いもの
Something precious
幼い僕らは
Our young selves
的外れだらけさ
Were full of misses
満ち足りた日々の 制圧は
The suppression of satisfying days
情緒不安定になる
Makes one emotionally unstable
傷を負ってでも
Even if I get hurt
羽ばたきたいと願うよ
I wish to flap my wings
愚かでもいいだろう
It's fine to be foolish
見渡す夢の跡
The traces of dreams looked upon
さよなら 蒼き日々よ
Goodbye, blue days
輝く空は
The shining sky
無邪気さを装い
Pretends to be innocent
全てを知っていた
It knew everything
僕らは目指した シャングリラ
We aimed for Shangri-La
欲望を抑えきれずに
Unable to restrain our desires
空想にまみれた
Covered in fantasies
自由を求め続けた
We continued to seek freedom
距離を置いてこそ
Only by keeping a distance
自由の大きさを知る
Do we know the scale of freedom
未熟な心は それさえ分からないまま
Our immature hearts still don't even know that
今なら言えるだろう
I can probably say it now
ここがユートピア
This place is Utopia
さよなら 蒼き日々よ
Goodbye, blue days
せーの！
One, two!
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that's not good enough
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
Look, that's no longer enough
心は進化するよ もっともっと
My heart will evolve, more and more
恋愛サーキュレーション
Lyrics: meg rock Composition: 神前 暁
Renai Circulation
Lyrics: meg rock Composition: Satoru Kosaki
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If it's a relationship that vanishes if put into words
言葉を消せばいいやって
I thought I should just erase the words
思ってた 恐れてた
That's what I thought, that's what I feared
だけど あれ？ なんか違うかも...
But wait? Maybe something is different...
せんりのみちもいっぽから！
A journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step!
石のようにかたい そんな意志で
With a will as hard as a stone
ちりもつもればやまとなでしこ？
If dust piles up, it becomes a Yamato Nadeshiko?
しんぬきで、いや死ぬ気で！
With all my soul, no, like my life depends on it!
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Fluffy and light, floating and soft
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで
Just you calling my name
宙へ浮かぶ
Makes me float into the air
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Floating and soft, fluffy and light
あなたが笑っている それだけで
Just you smiling
笑顔になる
Makes me smile too
神様 ありがとう
God, thank you
運命のいたずらでも
Even if it's a prank of fate
めぐり逢えたことが
The fact that we met
しあわせなの
Makes me happy
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that's not good enough
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
Look, that's no longer enough
心は進化するよ もっともっと
My heart will evolve, more and more
そう そんなんじゃ やだ
That's right, that's not enough, I don't want that
ねえ そんなんじゃ まだ
Hey, that's still not enough
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
Please keep watching me, forever and ever
私のこと 見ててね ずっとずっと
Please keep your eyes on me, forever and ever.
私の中のあなたほど あなたの中の私の存在は
As much as you exist within me...
まだまだ大きくないこともわかってるけれど
...I know that I don't yet exist as much within you.
今この同じ瞬間 共有してる実感
But the feeling of sharing this very moment right now...
ちりも積もればやまとなでしこ！
If dust piles up, it becomes a Yamato Nadeshiko!
略して？ ちりつもやまとなでこ！
Shortened? Chiritsumo Yamato Nadeko!
くらくらり くらくるる あなたを見上げたら
Dizzy-dizzy, spinning around, when I look up at you...
それだけで まぶしすぎて
...just that alone is too dazzling.
くらくるる くらくらり あなたを想っている
Spinning around, dizzy-dizzy, just thinking of you...
それだけで とけてしまう
...is enough to make me melt away.
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate...
めぐり逢えたことが しあわせなの
...being able to meet you makes me happy.
コイスルキセツハ
In the season of being in love...
ヨクバリ circulation
...it's a greedy circulation.
コイスルキモチハ
With feelings of being in love...
ヨクバリ circulation
...it's a greedy circulation.
コイスルヒトミハ
With eyes of being in love...
ヨクバリ circulation
...it's a greedy circulation.
コイスルオトメハ
As a maiden in love...
ヨクバリ circulation
...it's a greedy circulation.
ふわふわり ふわふわる あなたが名前を呼ぶ
Fluffy-fluffy, floating around, when you call my name...
それだけで 宙へ浮かぶ
...just that alone makes me float into the sky.
ふわふわる ふわふわり あなたが笑っている
Floating around, fluffy-fluffy, when you are smiling...
それだけで 笑顔になる
...just that alone makes me smile.
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate...
めぐり逢えたことが しあわせなの
...being able to meet you makes me happy.
でも そんなんじゃ だめ もう そんなんじゃ ほら
But that won't do, that won't do anymore, look...
心は進化するよ もっともっと
...my heart will evolve, more and more.
そう そんなんじゃ やだ ねえ そんなんじゃ まだ
Yes, I don't like it like that, hey, not like that yet...
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
...please keep your eyes on me, forever and ever.
Whew! And that was two songs in a row. Let's go!
Shangri-La and Ren'ai Circulation! Woo!
Ah, I hope you guys liked those.
I really like the gap between the two songs, you know,
Shangri-La from Fafner, watch Fafner, bam, it's like bam!
And then Ren'ai Circulation is like ooh, azatoi.
Alrighty then! Now that... after singing two songs,
I think it's time to welcome our very first guests!
Welcome, my friends from Hololive English Council!
IRyS!
IRyS! You did so great! Congratulations!
Congratulations! Oh my god!
You look so great!
You look so cute!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
Alrighty guys, please introduce yourselves one by one.
Okay! Who's going first? Me?
Me go first? Okay!
What's up! It's Hakos Baelz from Hololive EN Council,
representing Chaos!
Congratulations on 3D IRyS! Yay!
ありがとう！ Alrighty, next up, who wants to go next?
Thank you! Alrighty, next up, who wants to go next?
Me! Me! Me!
Yes! Okay!
You! You go you!
Oh hi! Oh hi! I'm Nanashi Mumei from
Hololive English Council, the Guardian of Civilization!
IRyS you look so nice today!
Thank you, Mumei!
Alrighty, and then next, who wants to go next?
Konfuna! It's me, Ceres Fauna!
IRyS, I'm obsessed with you right now.
Oh, really?
You're like a princess of my dreams.
Really? A princess?
お姫様、お姫様、お姫様。
A princess, a princess, a princess.
お姫様ですか？
A princess?
姫、姫！
Princess, princess!
The way you say "hime"
sounds a little sarcastic. Thank you.
Alrighty then, last but not least.
Oh hello everyone, it's Ouro Kronii from Hololive English Council,
the Warden of Time. IRyS...
Really, really liked your Shangri-La.
Yes! Thank you!
You were so out there.
Thank you.
Oh my god! Oh my god! Crazy.
Arigato. So cute. Oh my god.
Thank you. So cute. Oh my god.
Thank you guys! All righty then...
...since I have you guys here,
we are going to play a game with IRyS.
Yes. A game?
A game! What game?
A game that will test my acting skills. Yes!
It is called the "Let's test IRyS's acting skill"
game. Yeah, we didn't think of a name.
All righty. So first off...
...I will take some of the most iconic Japanese food,
which is, of course...
...Sushi! And green tea! Yay!
Whoa! Oh my god!
Thank goodness, I was getting hungry.
I know. I ate sandwich,
but I'm going to eat sushi after this. Yes.
I mean, during this, during this. Yes. Nice.
Alrighty, so for sushi, we have tuna,
or the maguro...
...wait, is the sushi showing up anytime soon?
Where's the sushi? Cast the spell! Magic sushi!
Magic... magic spell! Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo!
Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo! Sushi! Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo!
Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo! Sushi!
Oh, there we go! It worked!
It worked! Nice! Not only is she a princess,
she's a magic princess!
She is a magic princess!
Oh my goodness, it's gigantic!
Bigger than your face, bro.
Yeah, we're going to eat a lot of sushi today.
Alrighty, so there's the maguro,
and then there's the ika, the squid.
マグロのお寿司とイカのお寿司
どちらに大量ワサビが入っているでしょうか？
Tuna Sushi and Squid Sushi
Which has the most wasabi?
I'll eat them one by one, but one of those two
has a huge buttload of wasabi in it...
...while the other one doesn't.
But I'm going to try hard and pretend...
...actually, I'm going to pretend that both of them
have a lot of wasabi in it. Yes.
And you're supposed to guess which one actually
has the wasabi in it. Oh! Okay, okay.
Alrighty, first off, I'm going to eat the maguro.
Oh, you're starting already?
She's doing it already! Okay.
It's alright, she's easy to read.
Guys, it's fine. Watch her body language.
Oh! Oh! Okay. Okay. Okay.
Is she... is she for real?
What? Oh, okay. Okay.
Well, that's convincing!
That is pretty convincing. Oh!
鼻に... Oh, the sniffing, the sniffing!
The nose... Oh, the sniffing, the sniffing!
Pay attention, guys. Pay attention.
Did she just sniffle? To eat it?
She's on her... she's on her knees! Okay.
Is this too much? Is this too dramatic?
You think she's overreacting?
Oh my god, the aftertaste! Holy...!
Okay, okay, okay. Not bad, not bad. Alright, alright.
We're just like, analyzing her while she could
be in pain. She's so great.
The body movement! That was very convincing.
That was the maguro. That was the maguro. Okay,
now we're going to have the squid, the squid.
Alright, she's starting.
Oh! Oh!
Is she... too quickly? Too quickly, too early.
I think that was too quick.
I think that was too quick to turn easy.
Because, like, you know when you eat wasabi...
oh, she's back up.
Yeah, I think... her nose doesn't sound
blocked this time either.
You know how like when you sniff up?
Yeah, there should be like that sound.
Oh, she's overreacting! Too much, too much!
Overreacting after we said that!
Oh! I know that ika's going somewhere.
What? Oh, why is she sniffling so much now?
Hmm, are you overly aware? Is this reverse psychology?
I mean, I'd still be sniffling, even if this wasn't
the one that had the wasabi.
Even if, perhaps, this didn't have the wasabi,
I'd still be sniffling...
...because the first one was so wasabi-ful!
Exactly. Sniffling.
All righty guys, guess!
Guess which one had the wasabi in it!
I'm going to go with maguro. Maguro. First one. Tuna?
Final answer? Yeah, tuna. Tuna. Yeah.
Alrighty then, I guess I'll take that then.
Drumroll please!
Bam! Pin-pon! Yes!
The wasabi was in the maguro!
It was a lot of wasabi, holy smokes! Are you okay?
Like the moment I swallowed it, I was like,
"Oh shoot, I'm done". I was crying.
Okay. Alrighty then.
You guys, so if you get the right answer,
you get to request a pose for me!
So request away! Wait, do we get a pose each?
Uh, no, one pose from all of you, I think.
Oh, just one? Do you have any ideas?
I have one if no one else has one.
Oh!
You go, you go.
Okay. Alright, I don't know exactly
what this pose is,
but it has a name.
Mermaid Pose?
Whatever I think that is...
Mermaid pose?
Mermaid pose!
There's no reference.
Mermaid pose?
No reference?
I'm just gonna go for it with the name.
I have nothing to give you,
just based off the name, yeah.
Let's see Mermaid-RyS.
Give us your best mermaid.
Okay.
Okay. Since it's a mermaid,
there's probably no legs, right?
So... alright.
Pretend that I don't have legs, so... fins.
Can you make them flopping more sexy?
Yeah.
You look like a fish.
You literally look like a fish out of water.
That doesn't look like...
My knees!
Where's the maid part?
Stop! That's not a mermaid!
Alrighty, that was... that was my mermaid pose.
This doesn't look right, I know.
It doesn't.
Was it accurate?
Was it exactly what you were thinking?
Thank you.
It was around there. It was around there, yeah.
Alrighty then.
Magic cup. The magic cup.
Shut up! Shut up!
Alright, next up, tea.
Okay. First...
so one of the tea is very bitter
while the other one's probably not.
So we're gonna try it out, yeah?
I'm gonna pretend that both are equally bitter,
so it's the same trick.
Okay. Yes.
Which one was actually bitter.
Okay. Starting with the yunomi.
Pick it up in her hand? Yeah.
Ah, that was refreshing.
Phew! Okay.
Nice, she's going the other route. Okay.
Oh yeah, okay, okay.
It was very, very nice to eat this
after some spicy sushi.
Ah, that was good.
Did you just say eat this?
She's eating the tea?
I'm drinking!
She's nervous, she's lying!
Oh my god!
Ah! See, I'm taking...
I took another sip from this one, okay?
That was still my first one. Okay,
next one, second one.
From the glass.
B. Tea B.
Ah... ah...
Ah, that's some other... some good tea too.
It tastes slightly different.
I honestly can't tell the difference
between these two.
Nice refreshment after singing.
Alrighty.
Which one do you guys think it is
from my reaction?
They both look great.
Great tea.
Hmm... I think it's the first one.
I think it's the first one too.
What makes you think that?
Because you took a second sip of the
second tea without being prompted.
I didn't prompt the second one either.
No, no, no.
As in like you didn't prompt the second one,
you just went for a second sip,
but the first one, you made it very clear that
"look, oh, I'm taking a second sip now..."
Oh no!
I just thought it was because it was
the second time, that's why, you know,
for the second one. That's why I thought
it wasn't necessary to prompt.
Oh, she also paused...
She's really trying to convince us.
Yeah, she's trying...
Oh no! You guys have free opinions.
Free opinions.
She also paused slightly longer for
the first one as well.
True, you're right!
I'll take another sip for the first one.
Ah!
Oh!
I heard that! I heard that!
Gulp gulp gulp. It's fine.
She's really trying to convince us
it was not the first one.
Yeah, I don't know.
I think it's the first one.
You think it's the first one?
I don't know. I'm thinking the second one.
Can you drink the second one again?
Ah!
Oh!
That had a little... oh, that had a little
throat gurgle gargle though.
Oh now...
You know when you drink something bitter,
you have like that gag reflex
and your throat goes like all weird?
Her throat went weird for like a split second.
I feel like she's playing mind games.
I feel like it was the first one.
どっちだろうな...
I wonder which one it is...
どっちでしょうね...
Which one could it be?
どっちが苦いのかな...
I wonder which one is bitter...
どっちどっちどっちどっち...
Which one, which one, which one, which one...
Alrighty, which one?
Which? I'm fine with majority...
I'm actually not that sure.
I'm not sure either.
I think it's the... might be the second one. Yeah.
I think it's the second. Yeah.
Final answer?
I think second.
Second.
You guys got it right, the first one!
My sexy princess poses! Oh!
What was sexy princess pose?
I'll do it real quick if you...
I wanted to... oh!
What was your sexy princess pose?
Um, um... um... This one! Sexy princess!
Sexy princess pose!
What?
What is sexy princess pose?
Whatever pose you do.
Yes, yes, more, yes!
Oh yes! Perfect!
Yes, perfect! Beautiful!
Yes! Oh nice! Oh!
Oh my god.
I'm such an angel.
You guys gotta admit, I still answered your pleas.
Alrighty then. Thank you so...
Huh? What? Split?
Can you do a split?
No, no, no.
Shut up, no!
No! No, don't you...
No, no, I'm not. No, shut up.
You guys, we're running out of time, guys.
We're running out of time!
It's not because I can't do a split or anything.
It's because we actually don't have much... Oh, she's running away.
No, we actually don't have much time!
Alrighty... Yeah! Thank you guys so much for coming.
That was fun. That was fun.
Oh god, it was... yes!
Yeah! Thank you for having us! Thank you!
Thank you! Congratulations!
You're doing an amazing job!
Keep it up! Keep it up! Good job, good job!
We're all cheering for you!
Thank you!
Hope doesn't come back up. Bye-bye!
IRyS! Bye-bye! IRyS!
I don't have to say that. IRyS!
Alrighty then. That was fun.
Whoa! But looks like we don't have much time.
Our next guest is showing up.
Our next guest from JP.
JPからの次のゲスト様が登場します！
Our next guest from JP is appearing!
じゃあちょっと挨拶しに行こうかな、
Well, I'm going to go say hi,
...and go say hi to her and go change, yeah?
Okay, let's go meet her! Be right back!
海賊ならヨーホー
If you're a pirate, Yo-ho!
踊れ叫べヨーホー
Dance and shout, Yo-ho!
さあ今 旗のもとへ
Now, come gather under the flag!
宝鐘海賊団
The Houshou Pirates!
出航!
Setting sail!
Ahoy!! 我ら宝鐘海賊団☆
Ahoy!! We Are the Houshou Pirates☆
踊るアホウに見るアホウ
Dancin' fools and watchin' fools
全速前進だ!
Full speed ahead!
進め! 進め!
Forward! Forward!
最高は燦々 大航海日和だ
The sun is shining, it's a great day for a voyage
歌え! 歌え!
Sing! Sing!
最高のテンション 波の音に乗せて どんぶらこ
Peak tension, riding the sound of waves, bobbing along
海でガールズパーティー
A girls' party on the sea
おかげ兄貴がハッピー
Thanks to that, the boys are happy
踊らせて毒の牙 キラキラ
Let those poison fangs dance and sparkle
ええもん配れ バラまけ my house で夢を見て
Hand out good stuff, scatter it around, dream in my house
あぁ神様
Oh, dear God
いつかこのマリンを本物の海賊にしてください!
Please turn this Marine into a real pirate one day!
声をあげて さあ出航だ
Raise your voices, now it's time to set sail
我ら宝鐘海賊団
We are the Houshou Pirates
コンパス片手に旗を掲げ
With a compass in hand, raise the flag
この海をジャックしちゃおう
Let's hijack this sea
野郎共ついておいで
Follow me, you lot
共にヨーホー ヨーホー 叫ぼう
Let's shout Yo-ho! Yo-ho! together
最高のあの日々
Those best of days
喜ぼう 我が船
Let's rejoice, on our ship
踊るアホウに見るアホウ
Dancin' fools and watchin' fools
1, 2, さんばー! さんばー!
1, 2, Samba! Samba!
熱く 滾ろうよ熱唱
Let's boil hot and sing out
思いを解き放って
Release your feelings
赤く 煌めくパッション
Red, sparkling passion
形から入るタイプで
I'm the type who starts with the appearance
発射10秒前 走れ ガチ恋列車
10 seconds to launch, run, true-love train
夕焼けも照れるわ ギラギラ
Even the sunset is blushing, dazzling bright
滲む汗の滴る いい女 だけど
A fine woman dripping with sweat, but...
あぁ神様 船長はセンシティブだとBANされちゃうのですね
Oh God, the Captain will get banned if she's too sensitive, right?
般若!
Hannya!
奪われたら取り戻せ
If it's stolen, take it back
それが宝鐘海賊団
That's the Houshou Pirates
君達とならたどり着ける
With you all, we can reach it
伝説のエルドラド
The legendary El Dorado
よそ者 楽しみたけりゃ
Outsiders, if you want to have fun
歌えヨーホー ヨーホー パリナイ
Sing Yo-ho! Yo-ho! Party night
この景色
This scenery
大切な仲間よ
My precious comrades
言ったげ歌ったげ
I said it, I sang it
騒げや騒げ
Make some noise, make some noise!
踊るアホウに見るアホウ
Dancin' fools and watchin' fools
同じアホなら飲まなきゃ損損
Since we're all fools, you lose if you don't drink
坂樽片手に行きますよ それ!
With a sake barrel in hand, here we go! Heave-ho!
宝鐘マリン! 宝鐘マリン!
Houshou Marine! Houshou Marine!
世界で一番かわいいよ!
You're the cutest in the world!
メスガキメスガキ! エロガキエロガキ!
Bratty girl! Lecherous girl!
ボンキュッボン! お姉ちゃんパンツ何色?
Curvy girl! Big sister, what color are your panties?
パンツ履いてませーん!
I'm not wearing any panties!
お宝! お宝! モザイク! モザイク!
Treasure! Treasure! Censored! Censored!
弩S! 弩M! 撫でて! 撫でて!
Mega Sadist! Mega Masochist! Pet me! Pet me!
いざ！出航！
Set sail!
見てみたーい！
I want to see it!
もっと！もっと！
More! More!
うっふん
U-ffun!
もっと！もっと！
More! More!
セクシーに！
Make it sexy!
もっと！もっと！
More! More!
いやん！まいっちんぐ
Oh, no! I'm so embarrassed.
もっと！もっと！
More! More!
脱いじゃえ！
Take it off!
もっと！もっと！もっと！
More! More! More!
サビサビ！
Rust! Rust!
もっと！もっと！もっと！
More! More! More!
前前ギュッ！
Forward, forward, squeeze!
もっと！もっと！もっと！
More! More! More!
出航だー！
Set sail!
あぁ、もう！船長は君たちをそんな子に育てた覚えはありません！
Oh, come on! I don't remember raising you guys to be like that!
本当に... めっ！だぞ！
Really... Shame on you!
立てば乳、座れば尻、歩く姿は、センシティブ
Standing, boobs; sitting, butt; walking, sensitive.
夢を見よう この船で 後悔なんてさせない
Let's dream on this ship, I won't let you regret it.
君たちのおかげで私は 船長になれるから
Because thanks to you all, I can be a captain.
ミラクル船長かな？撃てー！
Am I a miracle captain? Fire!
ブッヒー！
Buhii!
声を上げて 出航だ 我ら宝鐘海賊団
Raise your voices, it's time to set sail! We are the Houshou Pirates!
コンパス片手に旗を掲げ この海をジャックしちゃうぞ
Compass in hand, flag raised, we're going to hijack this sea!
ヨーソロー ついておいで ともにヨーホー 叫ぼう
Yousoro! Follow along, let's scream "Yo-ho" together!
ああ 最高の連日 ヨーソロー 我が船
Ah, the best days! Yousoro, to my ship!
宝鐘の海賊団
The Houshou Pirates!
それでは行きますよ！
Here we go!
ヨーソロー！
Yousoro!
Stand By You
完成形を口に出すと しらけてしまいそうだから
If I speak of the final form, it seems like it might lose its charm.
音でかき消そう 無駄な防を気にしないでふざけ合いたい
So let's drown it out with sound, I want to mess around without worrying about useless defenses.
どんなにすごい本編よりも
More than any amazing main story...
色褪せない不滅の日々を重ねて歩きたい
I want to walk on, piling up unfading, eternal days.
Stand by you
いつも Stand by you
Always Stand by you
涙の波なら 並んで立っている
If it's a wave of tears, I'm standing right beside you.
Stand by you
いつも Stand by you
Always Stand by you
未来が灰になる 君と歌になる
The future turns to ash, but with you, it turns to song.
Stand by you
眠らない街の喧騒を抜け出して
Escaping the hustle and bustle of the city that never sleeps...
Stand by you
光溢れた夢の続きを君とともに
Continuing the light-filled dream, together with you.
正真正銘の感情 持て余すと上手く笑えなくなるから
Because if I have too much of my genuine emotions, I won't be able to smile properly.
一緒に燃やそう その思いを語り尽くして笑い合いたい
So let's burn them together, I want to talk out those feelings and laugh together.
どんなにすごい生涯よりも
More than any amazing lifetime...
君のそばにいられることが一番誇らしい
Being by your side is what I'm most proud of.
Stand by you
いつも Stand by you
Always Stand by you
涙の波なら 並んで立っている
If it's a wave of tears, I'm standing right beside you.
Stand by you
息をきらしていく 期待で汗ばんでいく
Running out of breath, sweating with anticipation.
君と明日へ行く
Going to tomorrow with you.
Stand by you
まばたきも忘れるほどの幸せで
With happiness that makes me forget to blink...
Stand by you
終わらせかけた話の先が生まれ始める
The end of the story I almost finished begins to be born.
たとえ 僕ら 遠く離れた場所へ行こうとも 変わらずにいたいよな 変わるはずがないよな
Even if we go to places far apart, I want us to stay the same. It shouldn't change.
You... いつもStand By You
You... always Stand By You
涙のターミナル Oh-oh-oh-oh...
A terminal of tears Oh-oh-oh-oh...
並んで立っている Stand By You
Standing side by side Stand By You
いつもStand By You
Always Stand By You
未来が灰になる Oh-oh-oh-oh...
Even if the future turns to ash Oh-oh-oh-oh...
君と歌になる Stand By You
I'll become a song with you Stand By You
Woah... woah... oh-oh...
眠らない街の喧騒を抜け出して Yeah! Stand By You
Escape from the bustle of the city that never sleeps Yeah! Stand By You
Woah... woah... oh-oh...
光溢れた夢の続きは君と共に Stand By You
The continuation of the dream overflowing with light will be with you Stand By You
Stand By You
Oh-oh... oh-oh...
Na-na-na-na-na... Stand By You
Oh-oh... Stand By You
Whew! And that was...
"Ahoy!!" with Marine-senpai and "Stand By You".
Thank you so much Marine-senpai for singing "Ahoy!!" with me.
I've always wanted to sing "Ahoy!!" ever since... ever since I got in...
ever since I got into Hololive, so I'm really happy I got that that wish granted.
Thank you so much. And "Stand By You",
my favorite song from HIGE DAN. HIGE DAN,
いいよね めちゃくちゃかっこいい。
they're good, aren't they? So cool.
すごくかっこいい。
Very cool.
Ah, and guess what? Time flies!
Like, I can't believe it. It was just like daytime just...
a few minutes ago. Now it's already nighttime!
Look how pretty this is. The moon is out.
Humongous moon! It looks like it's going to crash into Earth anytime soon.
And the sky is very clear. Look at the stars.
I'm so glad the weather is nice today.
No rain whatsoever. If there was rain, this show would have been canceled.
Damn it, thank God the weather gods have blessed me.
It's beautiful.
アレ？
Huh?
アレレレレ？ I thought I told you guys to stay at home!
Wha-wha-wha-what? I thought I told you guys to stay at home!
My little friends Bloom and Gloom are here!
Ah, they're so cute! Let me introduce them to you.
Um, this one is Gloom. This one is Gloom.
Say hi to camera, Gloom.
Say hi to the camera, Gloom.
Ah, 可愛いね！
Ah, so cute!
Hey! And this one is Bloom.
私の可愛いマスコットたち。可愛いね！
My cute mascots. So cute!
えい！
Hey!
Thank you guys so much for coming.
Ah, is there anything you guys want me...
want me to do with Bloom and Gloom today? The chat?
Chat, I'm watching you. Any sort of pose you want me to do with them?
I'll take maybe one request because we're running out of time.
One request if I can see in the comments. Hmm?
"Punch them"? Did I see it?
Did I see a comment to punch them?
Am I going to punch them?
You're going to take it, right? You're going to take it, right?
Okay... はぁっ！
Okay... Hah!
Okay... Sorry, sorry, sorry!
This is... this is fan service. There's nothing else I can do.
Okay, you're going to take it good, yeah? You're going to take it. Okay.
はぁっ！
Hah!
Hey! Alrighty.
Now I'm done with you two. I'm done with you two.
That was great. That was... they were great punching bags.
No, I'm sorry, I'm sorry! They're big hug, big hug, big hug!
Oh, no, no, you're scared. No, no, no. It's okay. Big hug, big hug.
I'm sorry! You guys are fine. You guys are...
you guys are very soft. You guys can handle it. We're fine.
Alrighty then! Thank you guys so much for coming, Bloom and Gloom.
I think it's about time you guys go rest, yeah?
Especially now that you've got that that big wound on your face.
Bye-bye-RyS! Bye-bye-RyS!
Alrighty then. We're getting to the end of the guest part,
but there's one more guest. One more special guest we have.
Let's welcome our final guest today with a song!
常世の闇に囚われたまま奏でる悲鳴を
With captured screams echoing in the eternal darkness
聞かせて...
Let me hear them...
爪を磨いたのは
I polished my nails...
まだ子どものようなあなたの為に
...for you, who are still like a child.
ああ 試されたいなら
Ah, if you want to be tested,
その愚かな手錠をかけて
put on those foolish handcuffs.
常夜の闇に囚われたまま
Trapped in the darkness of the night,
甘い甘いガムを噛んでて
keep chewing that sweet, sweet gum.
いくつもの幸福を
So many happinesses,
さあ 捧げて
come on, offer them up.
さりげない合図に隠れた
Hidden in a casual sign,
答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
I'll make you understand the answer soon.
美少な嘘にまみれた
Smeared with a faint smile and lies,
拒んだままに受け止めてあげる
I'll accept you just as you refuse.
ほら 悲鳴を聴かせて
Look, let me hear your screams.
さあ 指を鳴らしたら
Come, if I snap my fingers,
子猫のような私の為に
for me, who is like a kitten.
ああ 喉が渇いたわ
Ah, I'm thirsty.
薄紅の口に指を散らして
Scattering fingers on my pale red mouth.
狭い牢屋に閉じ込めたまま
Trapped in a narrow prison,
首輪に繋がれたいの
do you want to be tied to a collar?
下らないルールじゃ奪えない
You can't take it away with worthless rules,
自由はすでにこの手の中にある
freedom is already in my hands.
愛情では量れない
It cannot be measured by affection,
弱ったままに選ばせてあげる
I'll let you choose while you're weak.
ほら 心を開いて
Look, open your heart.
分からないフリをして
Pretending not to know,
惚けてるの？
are you being absent-minded?
もっと熱い暗闇を見せて
Show me a hotter darkness.
ねえ
Hey...
さりげない合図に隠れた
Hidden in a casual sign,
答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
I'll make you understand the answer soon.
美少な嘘にまみれた
Smeared with a faint smile and lies,
拒んだままに受け止めてあげる
I'll accept you just as you refuse.
常夜の闇に誘うこの名を
This name that invites into the darkness of night,
分からせてあげる
I'll make you understand.
ほら 悲鳴を聴かせてよ
Look, let me hear your screams.
夢見ないで
Don't dream.
ほら 聴かせて
Look, let me hear.
はい、今はトワ先輩の FACT でした！
Yes, that was Towa-senpai's "FACT"!
そして、本日最後のゲストのトワ先輩です！
And here is the final guest for today,
ご登場！
Towa-senpai! Welcome!
イェーイ！ホロライブ 4 期生の常闇トワ様です！
Yay! I'm Tokoyami Towa-sama from Hololive 4th Gen!
ヤッホー！ということで IRyS、3D 改めておめでとう！
Yahoo! So IRyS, congrats again on your 3D!
ありがとう！今日来てくれておつりりありがとう！
Thank you! Thanks for coming today, Otsu-Ri-Ri!
呼んでくれて嬉しかった！
I was happy you invited me!
しかもトワの曲の FACT 歌ってくれて嬉しかったよ！
And I was happy you sang Towa's song "FACT"!
絶対歌いたかった、これマジでかっこいい。
I definitely wanted to sing it, it's really cool.
え、しかもさ、デビューの時も Palette 歌ってくれたもんね、動画で。
And you also sang "Palette" when you debuted, in a video.
そう、2 回目！もうなんと 2 回目！
Yes, the second time! Already the second time!
嬉しい！じゃあということでトワも IRyS の曲をカバーしないとね。
I'm happy! So Towa should cover IRyS's song too.
いや、そのプレッシャー、プレッシャーをかけて！
No, that pressure, put pressure on me!
え、っていうかしていいの？
Wait, is it okay if I do?
あ、もちろん！ぜひぜひ聞きたい、聞きたいよ！
Ah, of course! I definitely want to hear it!
ということでいつかちょっと歌枠で披露しちゃおうかななんて思います。
So I'm thinking of performing it in a singing stream someday.
わーい！わーい！
Yay! Yay!
はい、ということで...
Yes, so...
実はこの二人、ちょっとどうですか？配信で二人きりみたいなのは。
Actually, these two... how is it? Being just the two of us on stream.
あんまりないよね。
Not much, right.
っていうかむしろほぼない。
Or rather, almost none.
そう、そうだよね。なんか大人数ではまああるけど。
Yeah, that's right. Like, in a large group there is, but...
もう二人ではちょっとあんまりないね。
But just the two of us, not really.
でも、実は結構遊んでたりしてね。
But, actually, we hang out quite a bit.
そうなの！そうなの、みんな、実はね。
That's right! That's right, everyone, actually.
そう、アフタヌーンティーに、カリもいたけど、カリと行ったりとか。
Yeah, we went to afternoon tea, Calli was there too, but with Calli...
あれめっちゃ美味しかった！
That was so delicious!
で、二人だけで夢の国行ったりとか。
And we went to the "Dreamland" just the two of us.
夢の国マジで感動したんだけど。あのショーとか。
Dreamland really moved me. That show and all.
もうショーを二人で見て、もう色々、いやーこれはいいねって。
We watched the show together and were like, "Wow, this is great."
トワたちもこんな感じでやりたいねなんて言って。
Towa and I said we wanted to do something like that.
あとスプラッシュでびしょ濡れ。
And getting soaked at Splash Mountain.
そう、びしょ濡れになったわ！マジで！
Yes, we got soaked! Seriously!
びしょ濡れだったね、あれマジ楽しかった！
We were soaked, that was seriously fun!
楽しかったね。そう、意外とね、裏じゃ、裏というかまあ配信外でちょっと遊んだりしてたんですよ。
It was fun. Yeah, unexpectedly, outside of streaming, we've been hanging out.
そう、だからこういう大きな場所でなんかトワ先輩と話すのはなんか、つい素、素が出ちゃう感じがして。
So, talking with Towa-senpai in a big place like this makes my true self come out.
いやー、いいよ、その素で嬉しいよ。
Well, that's fine, I'm happy you're being yourself.
しかもちょっと 3D で並ぶのも若干恥ずかしいところもあるわ。
And standing together in 3D is also a bit embarrassing.
何言ってんすか！トワ先輩可愛いじゃないですか！
What are you saying! Towa-senpai, you're cute!
ありがとう。スタイルがいい IRyS さん、ありがとうございます。
Thank you. Miss IRyS with the good figure, thank you very much.
ありがとう。この身長差が目立ちますけど。
Thank you. This height difference stands out though.
身長差可愛いよ！
The height difference is cute!
むしろそれがいい。
Actually, I like it that way.
ほんとに？むしろそれがいい？
Really? You like it that way?
アイリスの... いいな、からだ。
IRyS's... I like it, your body.
あ、そう。これからいっぱい牛乳飲めばいけんじゃない？
Oh, really? If I drink lots of milk from now on, I'll be fine, right?
牛乳飲めば、イエーイ！
Drink milk! Yay!
まあということでね、このあとも歌うんだよね？
Well then, we're going to sing another one after this, right?
うん、バリバリ歌います。
Yep, I'm gonna sing my heart out.
今日は誘ってくれてありがとう、本当に嬉しかった。
Thanks for inviting me today, I was really happy.
こちらこそありがとう、本当に。
The pleasure's mine, thank you, really.
めちゃくちゃ一緒に歌えてマジで。今後もトワ先輩みたいな歌歌えるように頑張るわ。
I'm so glad we could sing together. I'll do my best to sing like you, Towa-senpai.
えー、嬉しい、ありがとう。じゃあこの後の歌も頑張って。
Aw, that makes me happy, thanks. Good luck with the next song too.
はい！呼んでくれてありがとう！
Yes! Thanks for having me today!
ありがとう、バイバイ！またね！頑張れー！
Thank you, bye-bye! See ya! Good luck!
ばかみたい
Lyrics: 堀井亮佑 Composition: 福山光晴
Baka Mitai
Lyrics: Ryosuke Horii Composition: Mitsuharu Fukuyama
ばかみたい 子供なのね
I'm such a fool, just like a child
夢を追って 傷ついて
Chasing dreams and getting hurt
嘘が下手なくせに
Even though I'm a bad liar
笑えない笑顔みせた
I showed a smile that couldn't even laugh
I love youも ろくに言わない
I can't even say "I love you" properly
口下手で ほんまに不器用
So poor with words, truly clumsy
なのに なのにどうして
And yet, and yet, why
サヨナラは言えたの
Was I able to say goodbye?
だめだね だめよ だめなのよ
It's no good, no good, it's just no good
あんたが好きで 好きすぎて
I love you, I love you too much
どれだけ 強いお酒でも
No matter how strong the alcohol is
歪まない思い出が
Memories that won't blur
ばかみたい
What a fool
ばかみたい 本当バカね
What a fool, a real fool
あんた信じる ばかりで
Only ever believing in you
強い女のふり
Pretending to be a strong woman
切なさの夜風浴びる
Bathing in the night breeze of sadness
一人になって 3年が過ぎ
Three years have passed since I became alone
街並みさえも 変わりました
Even the cityscape has changed
なのに なのにどうして
And yet, and yet, why
未練だけ置き去り
Were only the lingering regrets left behind?
ほんまに ろくな男やない
Truly, you're a no-good man
揃いの指輪 はずします
I'll take off our matching rings
ざまあみろ せいせいするわ
Serve you right, I feel refreshed
いい加減 待ってても ばかみたい
Waiting forever is just foolish
だめだね だめよ だめなのよ
It's no good, no good, it's just no good
あんたが好きで 好きすぎて
I love you, I love you too much
どれだけ 強いお酒でも
No matter how strong the alcohol is
歪まない思い出が
Memories that won't blur
ばかみたい
What a fool
ほんまに ろくな男やない
Truly, you're a no-good man
揃いの指輪 はずします
I'll take off our matching rings
ざまあみろ せいせいするわ
Serve you right, I feel refreshed
ざまあみろ、せいせいするわ
Serves you right, what a relief.
なんなのよ、この涙
What are these tears?
馬鹿みたい
I've been a fool.
Ha...
And that was Baka Mitai!
You guys are probably wondering why Baka Mitai.
Because I wanted to sing it, that's why!
I've always wanted to sing it.
Ah, that was good stuff.
Alrighty then, but we're getting close to the ending, yes?
So I think it's about time we move.
I think it's really nice weather, nice nighttime.
I think it's now time for a nice night drive...
...toward the arena, In Arena!
Let's go by car!
So follow me! Follow me! Woo!
Hey guys, come here, come here.
Check out my new car!
Obviously, I'll drive.
You? You sit in the passenger seat.
You don't have a problem with that, right? Yeah, yeah.
Go sit over there.
So excited for this!
Shock!
Crazy for love!
Crazy for love, crazy for love, crazy for love, crazy for love...
Shock!
Crazy for love...
Got to be the first one, got to be the last one
You never get no peace of mind
Never show emotions, all communication's over
You got no feeling
Stop it now, guess you wonder why
You just sold out the dream inside
Up and down, baby for your lovin'
Baby we can fly up to the sky
Every day, every night, crazy for love
Into the depth of desire
Every time, everywhere, crazy for love
And now my spirit's on fire
Every day, every night, crazy for love
Into the depth of desire
Every time, everywhere, crazy for love
And now my spirit's on fire
Crazy for love...
Shock!
When you get that feeling, when you find some lovin'
You've got to run away from here
Show me your emotion, baby make me feel so natural
It's the real thing
Stop it now, guess you wonder why
You just sold out the dream inside
Up and down, baby for your lovin'
Baby we can fly up to the sky
Every day, every night, crazy for love
Into the depth of desire
Every time, everywhere, crazy for love
And now my spirit's on fire
Every day, every night, crazy for love
Into the depth of desire
Every time, everywhere, crazy for love
And now my spirit's on fire
Crazy for love...
Shock!
When you get that feeling, when you find some lovin'
You've got to run away from here
Show me your emotion, baby make me feel so natural
Baby make me feel so natural
It's the real thing
Stop it now, guess you wonder why
You just sold out the dream inside
Up and down, baby for your lovin'
Baby we can fly up to the sky
Every day, every night, crazy for love
Into the depth of desire
Every time, everywhere, crazy for love
And now my spirit's on fire
Every day, every night, crazy for love
Into the depth of desire
Every time, everywhere, crazy for love
And now my spirit's on fire
Crazy for love
Shock!
Got no feeling
Stop it now, guess you wonder why
Up and down, baby for your lovin'
Every day, every night, crazy for love
Every time, everywhere, crazy for love
Into the depth of desire
And now my spirit's on fire
Crazy for love
Shock!
Phew!
How was that drive?
I had a wonderful time with you guys, and we are here in one piece.
One piece, no harm whatsoever...
...we did not crash into anything.
Very safe, very fast drive.
And here we are at the EN Arena! Woo!
That was great.
And I sang so much, I'm getting a little tired.
I kind of think I need a drink.
Let me go get that drink.
Ey!
And what else would I drink than this, the Hope Soda!
Ah!
Ah, that's good stuff.
Isn't it cute? I love the can, it's so cute.
Ah, this is like the best soda on earth.
And maybe a lot of you guys haven't tried it...
...maybe a lot of you guys don't have it.
It's okay...
...because the merch today will be able to make up for it somewhat.
Because even if you don't have your own Hope Soda...
Bam!
HOPE Soda Can SleeveRyS (Can Sleeve)
Bam! You can use this Hope Soda can sleeveRyS...
...to turn your run-of-the-mill old soda, whatever it is, into Hope Soda.
At least feel like you're drinking Hope Soda. Let's go! Isn't it cute?
The nice refreshing red-pink and the cool black strap. Yes!
And it's getting very hot, so I think it's a nice time to, you know...
...have a nice cold drink, yes.
Keep your drink chilled...
...and your hands drip-free. Yay!
So, buy-RyS the sleeve-RyS!
Don't... not "bye-RyS", I mean B-U-Y-RyS.
Buy-RyS the sleeve, let's go!
Alrighty then.
It's really been reaching towards the very, very end.
It was a long journey, it's been what, two years?
Over two years since debut, and we're finally here with my 3D showcase.
I really wanted to do this.
Becoming 3D was one of my big reasons for wanting to join Hololive.
And actually being able to stand here doing this 3D...
...it's all thanks to you guys and your support. Thank you so, so much.
And yes, it's been a long two years and we're here...
...but it's the start of a new page.
And here's to many more years to come. Yay!
Alrighty then.
Well, I think it's time for the final song.
最後の1曲になるのかな？
I wonder if it'll be the last song?
怪しいね、さ、さ、最後の1曲になるかな、どうだろう？
Suspicious, isn't it? I wonder if it will be the final song, who knows?
Well, who knows, maybe you guys might want an encore, I don't know...
...or maybe you guys want me to just hurry up and get out.
I'm not done with, I don't know, but...
please listen to my final song,
my original song, BERSERKER.
BERSERKER
Lyrics: Spirit Garden Composition: 都丸喗太(Elements Garden)
Lyrics: Spirit Garden Composition: Kyota Tomaru (Elements Garden)
蔓延る不協和音 混沌のShow
The spreading dissonance, a show of chaos.
耳を塞いでも 搾取された日常
Even if I plug my ears, my daily life is exploited.
立ち上がれ 理不尽に喘いでも
Stand up, even if you're panting under the weight of injustice.
何人たりとも 此処は 奪わせないよ
I won't let anyone take this place away from me.
私が私であることが
That I am who I am...
私自身の正義だから
Is my own justice.
I know どんな結末になっても
I know no matter what the ending is.
後悔は1ミリもない
I don't have even a millimeter of regret.
Burn up
怒髪天 衝いて燃え盛れ 想いを懸けて Everything
Let your boiling anger reach the sky and burn brightly, stake your feelings on everything.
I'm a Berserker
塵と化せ 有象無象
Turn into dust, you rabble.
私の世界は 私のモノ 捧げるのは 希望
My world is mine, what I offer is hope.
Absolutely
高らかに
Loudly and clearly.
Absolutely
目覚めよ 今 Wake up
Awaken now, wake up.
並べ立てられた ご都合主義
Opportunism lined up one after another.
噛みつき剥ぎ取り 弱者は強者のPrey
Biting and tearing away, the weak are the prey of the strong.
立ち上がれ 不条理に泣いても
Stand up, even if you cry at the absurdity.
何人たりとも 此処は 汚させないよ
I won't let anyone defile this place.
私は私の言霊で
I, with my own spirit of words...
私自身と歩いてゆく
Will walk on with myself.
I know どんなに嗤われたって
I know no matter how much I'm laughed at.
恥ずべきことはない
There is nothing to be ashamed of.
Don't stop
進み続け 何度も生まれ変わりながら Fearless
Keep moving forward, being reborn over and over again, fearless.
I'm a Berserker
蹴散らして 有象無象
Scatter the rabble.
私の世界は 私のモノ 揺るがない真実を
My world is mine, the unwavering truth...
Absolutely
燦々と
Brilliantly.
Absolutely
目覚めよ 今 Wake up
Awaken now, wake up.
Burn up
怒髪天 衝いて燃え盛れ 想いを懸けて Everything
Let your boiling anger reach the sky and burn brightly, stake your feelings on everything.
I'm a Berserker
塵と化せ 有象無象
Turn into dust, you rabble.
私の世界は 私のモノ 捧げるのは 希望
My world is mine, what I offer is hope.
Absolutely
高らかに
Loudly and clearly.
Absolutely
目覚めよ 今 Wake up
Awaken now, wake up.
アンコール！ アンコール！
Encore! Encore!
え〜、そこまでみんな言うなら、しゃーないなー！
Eh? Since everyone's saying it that much, I guess I have no choice!
最後の1曲になります。
This will be the very last song.
Please listen to my last song for today, One Last Kiss.
One Last Kiss
Lyrics: Hikaru Utada
初めてのルーブルは なんてことはなかったわ
My first time at the Louvre was nothing special.
私だけのモナリザ もうとっくに出会ってたから
Because I'd already met my own Mona Lisa a long time ago.
初めてあなたを見た あの日動き出した歯車
The gears that started moving the day I first saw you...
止められない喪失の予感
The unstoppable premonition of loss.
もういっぱいあるけど
There's already so much, but...
もう一つ増やしましょう
Let's add one more.
Can you give me one last kiss?
忘れたくないこと
Things I don't want to forget
Oh oh oh oh...
I love you more than you'll ever know
写真は苦手なんだ
I'm not good at photos
でもそんなものはいらないわ
But I don't need anything like that
あなたが焼き付いたまま
While you're burned into
私の心のプロジェクター
The projector of my heart
寂しくないふりしてた
I pretended not to be lonely
まあ、そんなのお互い様か
Well, I guess we're in the same boat
誰かを求めることは
Seeking someone
即ち傷つくことだった
Means getting hurt in the process
Oh, can you give me one last kiss?
燃えるようなキスをしよう
Let's share a kiss as hot as fire
忘れたくても
Even if I want to forget
忘れられないほど
I can't forget you no matter what
Oh oh oh oh...
I love you more than you'll ever know
もう分かっているよ
I already know
この世の終わりでも
Even at the end of the world
年をとっても
Even if I grow old
忘れられない人
Someone I'll never forget
忘れられない
I'll never forget
I love you more than you'll ever know
吹いていった風の後を
Tracing the path of the wind
追いかけた 眩しい午後
I chased it on a dazzling afternoon
Thank you so much for coming everyone!
今日みんな来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you all for coming today!
ByeRyS!
Bye-ByeRyS!